manduka.com 2019-07-23

# Manduka | Privacy Policy

At Manduka LLC and Manduka B.V. (“Manduka,” “us,” “our,” or “we”), we recognize that your privacy is important – both to you and to us.  Manduka is also committed to the fair and transparent processing of our customers’, consumers’ and website visitors’ personal information (“Personal Information”). We also strive to ensure that you have the greatest possible control over your information. 

This Privacy Policy discloses our privacy practices as related to your access and use of Manduka’s websites, including all www.manduka.com and [www.mandukamag.com](http://www.mandukamag.com/) sites (“Site,” or “Sites” collectively), and the other products and services we may offer to you, such as the ability to make purchases of our products from our online store (“Purchases”), participate in or donate to Project: OM (“Project: OM”), or any other product or service that we make available to you (collectively, “Services”).  Our Policy is designed to advise you about how we use, protect, and disclose the information we receive or collect about you, explains your privacy rights, and how you can manage the privacy of your Personal Information.  Please read the following information carefully. 

Please note that this Policy does not govern the practices of third parties, such as our partners, third party service providers, and/or advertisers, even when those services are branded as being provided for Manduka or on Manduka’s behalf.  Any information you provide to a third party while utilizing their website or service will be governed by the third party’s privacy policy and/or terms of service.  Please read all third parties’ privacy policies and terms of service carefully.

  1. **Information We Collect**

We may collect certain information from you when you use our Services, including our Sites. That information includes:

**Personal Information** :  In order for you to register with Manduka, contact us with feedback or questions, request information from us, use certain functions on our Sites, or use certain Services offered, we may ask you to provide information about yourself.  Personal Information, **also known as “Personal Data,”** is any information that can be used to identify, locate or contact you.  This includes your name, physical address, email address, telephone number, and other identifying information.  It also includes other information that may be associated with your Personal Information, such as your location, IP address, preferences or interests.  Importantly, we may collect Personal Information directly from you when you visit our Sites. We will only collect Personal Information from you when you consent for us to do so, or if there is another permissible basis for collection (e.g. to fulfill a contract, or other legitimate interest).

At times, we may require you to provide certain Personal Information to use certain Services or fulfill your request – for instance, when you make a Purchase, we need to gather your name, address, and other Personal Information to fulfill your order.

Other services, such as those of Manduka’s third party payment providers, may require you to provide certain Personal Information like your payment card information (including expiration date and verification code) as well as your name, address, email address, and other information to complete a Purchase.

**Non-Personal Information (aka “Generic Information”)** :  In general, Manduka may also gather some generic information from out Site visitors automatically, but which does not reveal a visitor’s identity.  This includes the number and frequency of visitors to our Sites, the specific Manduka Sites and webpages visited, and the Sites or links clicked on, your language preference for accessing our Sites, your browser information and screen resolution, your device’s operating system, and your network service provider, among other information.  We gather this information for limited purposes, like determining our Site or customer service needs.

  2. **How We Collect Your Information**

Manduka collects and obtains your information in a few ways:  there is information that you choose to give to us, information we obtain through your use our Services – including our Site – and information we obtain from third parties.  Each of these is detailed below:

  1. **Information You Give to Us**

We collect certain information that you choose to share with us.  As noted above, sometimes this is information that we require in order for you to use our Services:  for instance, when you register for an account, we may ask you for your name, your address, your email address, and other identifying information about you.  We may also ask you to choose a password to protect your account.  We may require you to provide other information to use certain Services.

Additionally, we will collect information that you voluntarily provide through your use of the Site or other Services, such as when you sign up to receive our newsletter or contact us via email or direct message with questions, feedback, or comments about our, Sites, Services, or products.  In some areas of the Site, we may also ask you to provide information on your level of yoga expertise, the type of yoga you practice, your height, even your amount of perspiration.  We may also collect information that you place on publicly-available bulletin boards, product reviews, or other forums on our Sites.

  1. **Information We Obtain When You Use Our Services**

We also collect certain Personal Information and Generic Information from you through your use of our Services.  We may automatically collect your IP address and location data when you visit our Sites.

  * **Device** **Information** :  As noted above, we may collect certain information related to the device that you use to log into, access and use the Sites or other Services.
  * **Aggregate Information:**   We may use other aggregate information in relation to how you use our Sites or Services.

**Cookies** ****  
We may use “cookies” and other similar technologies to collect information about your activities.   This is so that we can customize certain aspects of your specific experience, and improve the overall function and efficiency of our Sites and Services.  Cookies are small data text files stored locally on your computer that uniquely identify your browser.  We may use cookies – for example, HiConversion, Bronto, Nosto, Hotjar, Double-Click, Google Analytics, and others – to perform various tasks such as: monitoring aggregate usage metrics, storing and remembering your passwords (if you choose this option), storing your account and advertising preferences you have set, and personalizing the Services we make available to you.  Manduka tracks user behavior over time and across other third-party websites or online services.

Our third-party service providers, third-party partners (such as retail partners), advertisers and other companies may use cookies or other similar technologies to collect your information and track your behavior.  These companies may collect information about your use of our Sites or Services and other online services over time and across different services.  Additionally, some companies may use information collected to deliver targeted ads on behalf of us or other companies, including on other websites or online services.  Manduka is not responsible for the functioning of cookies or other technologies used and placed by third parties on your device.

You may be able to control what cookies or other technologies your browser or mobile device accepts through your browser or mobile device settings.  Please refer to instructions provided by your mobile device’s manufacturer to determine whether you can limit the placement of and/or remove cookies or other technologies on your device.  Please note, however, that some aspects of our Services may not function properly if you elect to disable cookies, which could impact your Manduka experience.  Manduka does not respond to “do not track” browser signals.

**Other technologies**   
We may gather information about you automatically through your use of the Site, e.g., your IP address and how you navigate the Site. When you visit the Site, we may collect information by automated means, including technologies such as pixel tags, browser analysis tools, server logs and web beacons. This information is not personally-identifiable. We use this information to better understand, customize and improve user experience with our Sites, Services and offerings as well as to manage our advertising.

**Pixel tags:        **  Pixel tags and web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on website pages or in our emails that allow us to determine whether you have performed a specific action. When you access these pages or open or click an email, the pixel tags and web beacons generate a notice of that action. These tools allow us to measure response to our communications and improve our web pages and promotions.

**Other technologies:**   We collect many different types of information from other technologies to improve the quality of goods and services we provide. For example, we may collect information about the device you use to access our Site, your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. Our server logs also record the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. An IP address is a unique identifier that devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet.

In many cases, the information we collect using cookies and other tools is only used in a non-identifiable way, without any reference to your Personal Information. For example, we use information we collect about all website users to optimize our Sites and to understand website traffic patterns. We may aggregate and/or de-identify the data about visitors to our Site and use it for product and service development and to improve the quality of our products and Services. If we do associate the information we collect using cookies and other technology with your Personal Information, then it will become “Personal Information” and will be protected as described above.

  1. **Information We Obtain from Third Parties**

Manduka may allow you to sign up and log into our Sites using accounts you created with third party services, like Facebook (“Third Party Service Accounts”).  If you choose to login to the Sites using this method, the Third Party Service Account may ask your permission to share certain information from your Third Party Service Account with Manduka – such as your name, email address, and your Third Party Service Account profile data.   Such information is collected by the Third Party Service Account provider and shared with Manduka according to the Third Party Service Account provider’s privacy policies.

Manduka may collect information from various third parties about you, such as any third-party service providers who we use to provide our Services to you.  From time to time, we may also use or augment the Personal Information we have about you with information obtained from other sources, such as public databases, social media platforms and other third parties.  For example, we may use such third party information to confirm contact or financial information or to better understand your interests by associating demographic information with the information you have provided.

  3. **How We Use Your Information**

We will primarily use your information to provide you access to, and facilitate your use of our Sites and other Services.  For instance, we will use your information to personalize your Manduka experience when you use our Sites and other Services such as by customizing the content we provide to you, and by fulfilling purchases made through the Sites.

**Purposes for which we seek your consent.** We may also ask for your consent to process your personal information for a specific purpose that we communicate to you, for instance, to receive our newsletter and other such mailings you may be interested in. When you consent to our processing your personal information for a specified purpose, you may withdraw your consent at any time and we will stop processing of your data for that purpose.

  4. **How We Disclose or Share Your Information**

  1. **Other Users/Visitors**

Manduka will share your information with other Manduka users and visitors to our Sites who you interact with. For instance, we will provide and make publicly available information that you choose to give when posting to a public-facing Service on our Site, such as a bulletin board or a product review. This information may include your name, your profile information, and other information that you choose to include. We may also share additional information with other Manduka users that you have permitted through your settings. We may also share any additional information that you have consented for us to share.

  1. **Disclosure of Your Information**

Manduka does not sell, trade, or rent your Personal Information to others, except in the limited ways outlined in this policy. Manduka may release or disclose your information to third-party service providers or agents who perform functions on our behalf or who facilitate the provision of our Services to you. For instance, we may need to provide your user account information to our data hosting and data processing service providers. Additionally, we may release or disclose your information to third-party partners, such as retail partners who may be able to provide you additional Manduka-related information, goods, or services.

Please be aware that any third-party’s use of your information is governed by their respective privacy policies, not this Policy. The privacy practices of third parties are not subject to our control, and Manduka is not responsible for the policies and practices of third parties.

Manduka may share information with other Manduka entities. We may also share your information in relation to a merger, sale, financing, acquisition or other transaction involving all or a part of Manduka with another company.

We may also be required to disclose your information in response to a lawful and enforceable request by law enforcement, judicial body, or other public authorities, or in connection with a legal obligation. In such instances, we will disclose your Personal Information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or other lawful and enforceable process, or where otherwise required by law.

We reserve the right to report to law enforcement any information – including Personal Information – related to the use of our Services used to further any unlawful activity or activity we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

  5. **International Transfers of Your Information**

If you are visiting this site or utilizing services from a country other than the United States or Canada, the various communications you send and receive will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international boundaries. If you are located in the European Union you should be aware that information you provide or which is otherwise collected on this Site or through any services rendered may be transferred to countries (including the United States) which do not have data protection laws deemed as adequate as those in the EU.

In cases where Manduka needs to transfer Personal Information outside the European Union, we shall ensure that adequate safeguards, as required under applicable data protection legislation, will be implemented (including, as applicable, the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses, as appropriate).

  6. **How Long Do We Keep Your Information?**

We keep your Personal Information to enable your continued use of Manduka’s Services, for as long as it is required in order to fulfil the relevant purposes described in this Privacy Policy, as may be required by applicable law, as necessary to protect our rights and interests, or as otherwise communicated to you. For example, we may retain your transaction history so that you can review past purchases (and repeat orders if desired) and what addresses you have shipped orders to, and to improve the relevancy of products and content we recommend.

  7. **Your Privacy Rights**

Manduka will ensure that you can exercise your rights pertaining to your Personal Information, including rights as provided by various data protection laws. Manduka therefore informs you that, where applicable under relevant law, you are entitled:

    * to have access to your Personal Information upon simple request – that is, you may receive a copy of such data (if requested), unless such data is made directly available to you, for instance within your personal account;
    * to have access upon simple request, and free of charge, the categories and names of addresses of third parties that have received Personal Information for direct marketing purposes;
    * to obtain a rectification of your Personal Information should it be inaccurate, incomplete or obsolete;
    * to obtain the deletion of your Personal Information in the situations set forth by applicable data protection law (the “right to be forgotten”).
    * to withdraw your consent to the data processing without affecting the lawfulness of processing, where your Personal Information has been collected and processed on the basis of your consent;
    * to object to the processing of your Personal Information (where it has been collected and processed on the basis of legitimate interests of Manduka) in which case we may ask you to justify your request by explaining to us your particular situation;
    * to request a limitation of the data processing in the situations set forth by applicable law;
    * to have your Personal Information directly transferred by Manduka to a third-party processor of your choice (where technically feasible and when processing is based on your consent); and
    * to non-discrimination, as defined under relevant law, in the Services or quality of Services you receive from us for exercising your rights.

Under certain laws, you may also have the right to “opt-out” of having your Personal Information sold to a third party. However, Manduka does not sell your Personal Information to any other party. Only in the case of a merger, sale, financing, acquisition, or other transaction involving all or part of Manduka may your information be involved in a transaction.

For deletion/”right to be forgotten” requests, we will undertake a good faith effort to accommodate requests for access to or deletion of personal information. However, these requests may be subject to the evaluation of additional factors, including disproportionate burden or expense, or the risk to the rights, including the privacy rights, of others.

We will strive and work to resolve any inquiry you may have regarding our privacy practices. EU residents may also file a complaint before a competent data protection authority regarding the processing of your Personal Data. While we suggest that you contact us beforehand, if you wish to exercise this right, you should contact the competent data protection authority directly.

If you have any questions, would like to exercise any of these rights, or if you need any assistance with privacy related matters, please contact us as described in the “Contact Us” section below. We will take the necessary steps to respond to you as soon as possible.

  1. **Your Choices on Collection and Use of Information**

You may change certain preferences in your account regarding the sharing and use of your information on our Site by visiting your account settings. Please note that some Site functionality may be impacted depending on the preferences you choose.

Manduka also offers individuals the opportunity to choose or “opt-in” to receive emails or other communications from us and/or our partners regarding offers, products, and services we feel may interest you. We will ask you if you want to receive such emails before we begin sending them to you. If have opted in to receive such communications from us but later decide you do not want to receive solicitations from us or our partners related to your account with us, you always can “opt-out” by accessing and editing your account information to no longer receive such offers and mailings, or by following the “unsubscribe” directions attached to such emails.

You also have the ability to change your browser’s and your device’s cookie settings, as described above.

  1. **Updating and Correcting Your Information**

You can always update your basic account information by logging into your Manduka account. If you need to access, update, or delete other Personal Information we may have in another way or manner, please contact us at the address below. Note that we may limit additional requests to modify your Personal Information, such as if your request impacts other users’ privacy, concerns information that Manduka does not possess or control, is repetitive, is unlawful, or requires technical means disproportionate to the request.

  8. **Protecting Your Information**

At Manduka, we take reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect your information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, and destruction.

While we strive to make your information as secure as possible, no transmission system or data network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, you acknowledge that there are data security and privacy limitations inherent to the Internet, and that the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information exchanged between you and Manduka, and between you and other Manduka users, cannot be guaranteed.

  9. **Children**

All of Manduka’s Services – including our Sites – are intended for adult audiences, and are not intended for or directed to anyone under 16 years of age. We therefore do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 16 years of age. If you are under 16 years of age, do not attempt to register for or use any Service provided by Manduka, and do not provide us any Personal Information about yourself.

  10. **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

The most current version of our Policy is accessible on our Site at all times. We reserve the right to make changes to our Policy at any time and at our sole discretion. We encourage you to review the Policy from time to time to ensure that you are familiar with our practices, and aware of any changes. In addition, we will notify you via email or alert on our Sites if we make material changes to the Policy and what those material changes may be.

  11. **Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who have supplied Personal Information, as defined in the statute, to us to request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If this applies, you may obtain the categories of Personal Information shared and the names and addresses of all third parties that received Personal Information for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2017 will receive information about 2016 sharing activities). To make such a request, please provide sufficient information for us to determine if this applies to you, attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. You may make this request in writing to us at the below address. Any such request must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this address.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this Policy or our privacy practices, you can contact us at:

Manduka, LLC  
Attn: Steven Hosokawa   
2121 Park Place Suite 250   
El Segundo, CA 90245  
Toll-free: 877.626.3852

Manduka B.V.  
Attn: Steven Hosokawa   
555 Keizersgracht, Amsterdam 1017DR, The Netherlands  
+31 800.626.3852

Or by email at: DMCA@manduka.com

Please note that Manduka is not responsible for the content or practices of third party websites or services to which Manduka may link through our Sites. Your interaction with all third party service providers’ websites is governed by the applicable third party privacy policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of such third party providers before using their sites or services.

Effective: August 1, 2018
